Register of the Alfred Max Loewenthal papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- ELECTRICAL WORKERS' UNIONS FILE, 1935-1979 (Boxes 2-16)
  - UE publications, 1937-1968
    - 1955-1968 (Box-folder 11: 1)
      Mainly UE newspaper coverage of findings of fraud in 1964 IUE elections and subsequent investigations of IUE finances. Includes UE pamphlets, Financial Corruption and Election Frauds in IUE and IUE Financial Corruption, reprinting U.S. Department of Labor and internal IUE findings.
  - IUE convention proceedings, 1949-1968
    - Organizational convention, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1949 (Box-folder 11: 2)
    - 2nd annual convention, Milwaukee, Wisconsin, 1950 (Box-folder 11: 3)
    - 3rd annual convention, Buffalo, New York, 1951 (Box-folder 11: 4)
    - 4th annual convention, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, 1952 (Box-folder 12: 1)
    - 5th annual convention, Montreal, Quebec, 1953 (Box-folder 12: 2)
    - 6th annual convention, Miami Beach, Florida, 1954 (Box-folder 12: 3)
    - 1st biennial economic policy conference, Cincinnati, Ohio, 1955 (Box-folder 12: 4)
    - 7th constitutional convention, St. Louis, Missouri, 1956 (Box-folder 13: 1)
    - 8th constitutional convention, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1958 (Box-folder 13: 2)
    - 9th constitutional convention, Miami Beach, Florida, 1960 (Box-folder 13: 3)
    - 10th constitutional convention, Cleveland, Ohio, 1962 (Box-folder 14: 1)
    - 11th constitutional convention, Washington, D.C., 1964 (Box-folder 14: 2)
    - 12th constitutional convention, Miami Beach, Florida, 1966 (Box-folder 14: 3-4)
    - 13th constitutional convention, New York, New York, 1968 (Box-folder 15: 1)
  - IUE publications, 1950-1979
    Issues of, and articles from, IUE News, issues of District Three Leader, issues of local newsletters, and miscellaneous international office and local publications.
    - 1950-1959 (Box-folder 15: 2)
      Includes Local 447 Constitution and By-Laws.
    - 1963-1964 (Box-folder 15: 3)
    - 1967 (Box-folder 15: 4)
      Includes IUE International Constitution.
    - 1968-1979 (Box-folder 15: 5)
      Includes Local 463 Mission to Southeast Asia report.
  - Industry publications, 1944-1962 (Box-folder 15: 6)
    Serial issues, pamphlets, and public relations issuances issued by the Federal Radio and Telephone Company (employer of Local 447 workers) and the International Telephone and Telegraph Corporation, of which it became a subsidiary.
  - Press coverage, 1948-1969
    Clippings and journal articles from the mainstream press relating to electrical workers' unions.
    - 1948-1962 (Box-folder 16: 1)
      Includes coverage of expulsion of UE from Congress of Industrial Organizations.
    - 1963-1965 (Box-folder 16: 2)
      Includes coverage of disputed IUE election of 1964 and overturn of results.
    - 1966-1969 (Box-folder 16: 3)
      Includes coverage of investigations of IUE finances and ouster of District 3 officials.
  - James B. Carey oral history, undated (Box-folder 16: 4)
    Photocopy of 204-page "Oral Autobiography of James B. Carey," longtime president of the IUE. Includes photocopies of miscellaneous biographical material relating to Carey.
- LABOR EDUCATION FILE, 1922-1978 (Boxes 16-19)
  Papers relating to formal programs for education and leadership training of union members, especially the Union Leadership Academy, conducted at the Rutgers University Institute of Management and Labor Relations, in conjunction with the IUE and the Cornell University School of Industrial and Labor Relations.
  - General, 1951-1969
    Programs, agenda, newsletters, notes, certificates, leaflets, flyers, and financial records.
    - 1951-1954 (Box-folder 16: 5)
      Includes material on IUE District 4 Leadership Institute.
    - 1955-1956 (Box-folder 16: 6)
      Includes material on Union Leadership Academy, and Labor Editors' Conference at Rutgers University.
    - 1957 (Box-folder 17: 1)
      Includes material on Union Leadership Academy, and Labor-Management Conference at Rutgers University.
    - 1958 (Box-folder 17: 2)
      Includes material on Union Leadership Academy, Labor Editors' Conference at Rutgers University, Cornell University Conference on Building Union Democracy, and New Jersey Leadership Program for Liberal Adult Education.
    - 1959-1960 (Box-folder 17: 3)
      Includes material on Union Leadership Academy, IUE local programs, and Instituto de Relaciones del Trabajo at the Universidad de Puerto Rico.
    - 1961 (Box-folder 17: 4)
      Includes material on Union Leadership Academy, IUE local programs, Newark Unemployed Out-of-School Youth Conference, Newark Youth Council Conference, and Instituto de Relaciones del Trabajo at the Universidad de Puerto Rico.
    - 1962 (Box-folder 17: 5)
      Includes material on Union Leadership Academy, and Mercer County (New Jersey) Industrial Commission conferences.
    - 1963-1965 (Box-folder 17: 6)
      Includes material on Union Leadership Academy, Newark Unemployed Out-of-School Youth Conference, and St. Peter's Institute of Industrial Relations courses.
    - 1967-1969 (Box-folder 17: 7)
      Includes material on Rutgers University Institute of Management and Labor Relations programs.
  - Correspondence, 1948-1974
    - General, 1951-1969
      - 1951-1953 (Box-folder 17: 8)
      - 1954-1955 (Box-folder 18: 1)
      - 1956-1959 (Box-folder 18: 2)
      - 1960-1969 (Box-folder 18: 3)
    - AFL-CIO. Department of Education, 1957-1966 (Box-folder 18: 4)
    - Addonizio, Hugh J., 1962-1964 (Box-folder 18: 5)
    - American Labor Education Service, 1953-1961 (Box-folder 18: 6)
    - Collins, George R., 1952-1955 (Box-folder 18: 7)
    - Congress of Industrial Organizations. New Jersey State Council, 1951-1956 (Box-folder 18: 8)
    - Cornell University. School of Industrial and Labor Relations, 1953-1957 (Box-folder 18: 9)
    - Jennings, Paul, 1953 (Box-folder 18: 10)
    - Minish, Joseph G., 1955-1963 (Box-folder 18: 11)
    - New Jersey. Department of Education, 1956-1964 (Box-folder 18: 12)
    - New Jersey. Rehabilitation Commission (Beatrice Holderman), 1960-1965 (Box-folder 18: 13)
    - New Jersey Council on Economic Education, 1953-1965 (Box-folder 18: 14)
    - Newark College of Engineering, 1954-1968 (Box-folder 18: 15)
    - Reuther, Victor G., 1954 (Box-folder 18: 16)
    - Ross, Sam (re Puerto Rico), 1956 (Box-folder 18: 17)
    - Rutgers University (including its Institute of Management and Labor Relations), 1948-1974
      - 1948-1962 (Box-folder 18: 18)
      - 1963-1974 (Box-folder 18: 19)
    - Segal, Ben, 1960-1961 (Box-folder 19: 1)
    - United States. Agency for International Development (Emil G. Lindahl), 1963 (Box-folder 19: 2)
    - United States. Department of Labor, 1957-1962 (Box-folder 19: 3)
    - Weihrauch, Milton, 1953-1956 (Box-folder 19: 4)
  - Publicity, 1953-1970
    Press releases, clippings, and journal articles about labor education programs and especially about Loewenthal's participation in labor education programs.
    - 1953-1956 (Box-folder 19: 5)
    - 1957 (Box-folder 19: 6)
    - 1958-1959 (Box-folder 19: 7)
    - 1960-1970 (Box-folder 19: 8)
  - Printed articles about labor education programs in general, and about American Federation of Labor and AFL-CIO public positions with regard to education, 1922-1978 (Box-folder 19: 9)
- ELECTION CAMPAIGN FILE, 1962-1964 (Boxes 19-20)
  Papers relating to election campaigns of Alfred Loewenthal for mayor of Verona, New Jersey in 1963, and for Congress in the 12th Congressional District of New Jersey in 1964.
  - Correspondence, 1962-1964
    - General, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 19: 10)
    - Addonizio, Hugh J., 1963 (Box-folder 19: 11)
    - Democratic Party (county, state and national offices), 1962-1964 (Box-folder 19: 12)
    - Hughes, Richard J., 1964 (Box-folder 19: 13)
    - Kennedy, Robert F., 1964 (Box-folder 19: 14)
    - Liberal Party of New York State (Charles S. Zimmerman), 1963-1964 (Box-folder 19: 15)
    - McCarthy, Eugene J., 1964 (Box-folder 19: 16)
    - Minish, Joseph G., 1963 (Box-folder 19: 17)
    - Williams, Harrison A., Jr., 1963-1964 (Box-folder 19: 18)
  - Campaign literature, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 20: 1)
    Leaflets, flyers, announcements, and press releases.
  - Press coverage, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 20: 2)
    Clippings and journal articles.
  - Election return statistics, 1962-1964 (Box-folder 20: 3)
  - Miscellany, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 20: 4)
    Ballots, election district maps, memoranda, notes, and background material on local issues.
- AMERICAN FEDERATION OF TEACHERS FILE, 1966-1980 (Boxes 20-27)
  Papers relating to the American Federation of Teachers.
  - General, 1966-1980
    Memoranda, reports, notes, programs, agenda, schedules, meeting materials, curricula vitae, lists, and financial records.
    - 1966-1973 (Box-folder 20: 5)
    - 1974-1976 (Box-folder 20: 6)
    - 1977 (Box-folder 20: 7)
    - 1978 (Box-folder 21: 1-2)
      Includes proposed book outline by Albert Shanker, report on investigation of AFT Boston local, report on AFT unionization drive at the State University of New York/Buffalo, and Social Democrats, U.S.A. report on unions in Portugal, Spain, and Italy.
    - 1979 (Box-folder 21: 3-4)
      Includes testimony by Albert Shanker on proposed U.S. Department of Education, report by Robert Nielsen on independent higher education unions, material on grass roots organizing, and material on international activities in general.
    - 1980 (Box-folder 21: 5)
  - Correspondence, 1967-1979
    - General, 1967-1979
      - 1967-1971 (Box-folder 21: 6)
      - 1972-1974 (Box-folder 21: 7)
      - 1975-1977 (Box-folder 21: 8)
      - 1978-1979 (Box-folder 21: 9)
    - AFL-CIO (national office; Irving Brown, Lane Kirkland, Ernest S. Lee, George Meany), 1969-1979 (Box-folder 22: 1)
    - African-American Labor Center (David Brombart, Patrick J. O'Farrell), 1978-1979 (Box-folder 22: 2)
    - American Institute for Free Labor Development (William C. Doherty, Jr.), 1979 (Box-folder 22: 3)
    - American Jewish Committee, 1968-1973 (Box-folder 22: 4)
    - American Labor History Series, Inc., 1978-1979 (Box-folder 22: 5)
    - Anti-Defamation League of B'nai B'rith, 1973 (Box-folder 22: 6)
    - Asian-American Free Labor Institute, 1979 (Box-folder 22: 7)
    - Bayh, Birch, 1973 (Box-folder 22: 8)
    - Carter, Jimmy, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 22: 9)
    - Cogen, Charles, 1967-1970 (Box-folder 22: 10)
    - Democratic Party (local and national offices), 1969-1971 (Box-folder 22: 11)
    - Free Trade Union Institute, 1979 (Box-folder 22: 12)
    - Goldberg, Harry, 1975 (Box-folder 22: 13)
    - Gravel, Mike, 1971 (Box-folder 22: 14)
    - Green, Angela, 1979 (Box-folder 22: 15)
    - Histadrut (General Federation of Labor in Israel, American Trade Union Council for Histadrut, American Histadrut Cultural Exchange Institute), 1970-1979 (Box-folder 22: 16)
    - Humphrey, Hubert H., 1976 (Box-folder 22: 17)
    - International Labour Office, 1976 (Box-folder 22: 18)
    - International Ladies' Garment Workers Union, 1973-1975 (Box-folder 22: 19)
    - Israel. Embassy (U.S.), 1970-1979 (Box-folder 22: 20)
    - Jackson, Henry M., 1975-1976 (Box-folder 22: 21)
    - Jewish Labor Committee (Emanuel Muravchik), 1968-1979 (Box-folder 22: 22)
    - Kennedy, Edward M., 1969-1975 (Box-folder 22: 23)
    - Kennedy, Robert F., 1968 (Box-folder 22: 24)
    - League for Industrial Democracy, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 22: 25)
    - McGovern, George, 1971 (Box-folder 22: 26)
    - Minish, Joseph G., 1970 (Box-folder 22: 27)
    - Morris, Gerald, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 22: 28)
    - Nader, Ralph, 1977 (Box-folder 22: 29)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities, 1976-1978 (Box-folder 22: 30)
    - National Strategy Information Center (Frank R. Barnett), 1975-1976 (Box-folder 22: 31)
    - Newark Human Rights Commission, 1968 (Box-folder 22: 32)
    - Pryor, David, 1971 (Box-folder 22: 33)
    - Ribicoff, Abraham, 1973 (Box-folder 22: 34)
    - Shanker, Albert, 1971 (Box-folder 22: 35)
    - Social Democrats, U.S.A. (Carl Gershman, Bayard Rustin), 1979 (Box-folder 22: 36)
    - Stevenson, Adlai E., III, 1973 (Box-folder 22: 37)
    - Streat, W. L., 1972 (Box-folder 22: 38)
    - Textile Workers Union of America, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 22: 39)
    - U.S. Committee for Democracy in Greece (Melina Mercouri), 1968 (Box-folder 22: 40)
    - United States. Department of Commerce, 1968-1979 (Box-folder 22: 41)
    - United States. Department of Defense, 1969 (Box-folder 22: 42)
    - United States. Department of Health, Education and Welfare, 1969-1975 (Box-folder 22: 43)
    - United States. Department of Labor (Ray Marshall), 1968-1979 (Box-folder 22: 44)
    - United States. Department of State (Emil G. Lindahl), 1967-1979 (Box-folder 22: 45)
    - White House Conference on Youth, 1971 (Box-folder 22: 46)
    - Wolfe, Bertram D., 1974 (Box-folder 22: 47)
    - Workmen's Circle, 1969 (Box-folder 22: 48)
    - Young People's Socialist League, 1975 (Box-folder 22: 49)
  - Labor History Exhibit, Garment Center, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 23: 1)
    Correspondence, program, speech, and printed matter. Includes printed article by Albert Shanker.
  - National Manpower Institute, 1979 (Box-folder 23: 2)
    Meeting materials and research papers re its Worker Education and Training Policies Project.
  - National Retired Teachers Association, 1972-1977 (Box-folder 23: 3)
    Pamphlets and bulletins.
  - Yeshiva case (National Labor Relations Board vs. Yeshiva University; Yeshiva University Faculty Association vs. Yeshiva University), 1978-1980 (Box-folder 23: 4)
    Supreme Court decision, correspondence, and memoranda re case involving faculty collective bargaining.
  - Writings by others, 1972-1979
    - Cook, A. Samuel, "Public Employee Unionism,", circa 1976 (Box-folder 23: 5)
    - Garbarino, Joseph W., "Faculty Bargaining and Proposition 13 Come to California,", 1979 (Box-folder 23: 6)
    - Golden, Carl, "A Resource Book for the Teaching of Labor in American History and Economics,", 1972
      - Typescript (Box-folder 23: 7-8)
      - Publishers' correspondence and evaluations by Thomas R. Brooks and others (Box-folder 24: 1)
    - Haynes, Don, untitled history of AFT, 1973
      - Typescript (Box-folder 24: 2)
      - Publishers' correspondence, evaluations, and related materials (Box-folder 24: 3)
    - Polishook, Irwin H., "Tenure, Unionization and Collective Bargaining in American Higher Education: The Recent Experience,", 1977 (Box-folder 24: 4)
    - Ward, James G., 1978-1979
      - "The Tax Limitation Movement: The Facts and Issues,", 1978 (Box-folder 24: 5)
      - "School District Budget Analysis: A Training Manual,", 1979 (Box-folder 24: 6)
  - Grant proposals, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 24: 7)
    AFT proposal to National Endowment for the Humanities for project on the history of collective bargaining and faculty governance in academia (Loewenthal and Robert Nielsen, principal investigators), 1977; proposal to establish the feasibility of producing a 52-volume social history of working people in America, 1979.
  - AFT minutes, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 24: 8)
    Executive Council draft minutes.
  - AFT conventions, 1973-1979
    - 57th annual convention, 1973 (Box-folder 24: 9)
      Officers' reports.
    - 61st annual convention, Boston, Massachusetts, 1977 (Box-folder 24: 10)
      Program.
    - 62nd annual convention, Washington, D.C., 1978 (Box-folder 24: 11)
      Resolutions and report on convention by National Education Association.
    - 63rd annual convention, San Francisco, California, 1979 (Box-folder 25: 1)
      Program, reports, resolutions, correspondence and memoranda.
  - AFT publications, 1968-1980
    - American Educator, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 25: 2-3)
    - American Teacher, 1976-1980 (Box-folder 25: 4-5)
    - Constitution, 1977 (Box-folder 25: 6)
    - Regional publications, 1970-1980
      - The Anatomy of a Strike (Newark Teachers Union), 1970 (Box-folder 26: 1)
      - The Story of Labor in American History (Minnesota Federation of Teachers), 1972 (Box-folder 26: 2)
      - Miscellaneous, 1973-1980 (Box-folder 26: 3)
    - Shanker, Albert, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 26: 4)
      Printed articles.
    - State of the Union reports, 1976-1979
      - 1976-1977 (Box-folder 26: 5)
      - 1977-1978 (Box-folder 26: 6)
      - 1978-1979 (Box-folder 26: 7)
    - Miscellany, 1968-1980 (Box-folder 26: 8)
      Leaflets, reprints, bulletins, and bibliography.
    - Press coverage, 1969-1980 (Box-folder 26: 9)
      Clippings and press compilations about the AFT.
    - Printed articles about the AFT, 1968-1980
      - 1968-1976 (Box-folder 26: 10)
      - 1978-1980 (Box-folder 27: 1)
        Includes articles by George N. Schmidt in Substance and review article in Covert Action Information Bulletin relating to ties between the AFT and the Central Intelligence Agency.
- INTERNATIONAL TEACHERS' UNIONS FILE, 1971-1980 (Boxes 27-29)
  Papers relating to international teachers' unions.
  - Correspondence, 1977-1980
    - International Federation of Free Teachers' Unions (André Braconier, David Dorn, Michael Senoo, Gurnam Singh), 1977-1979 (Box-folder 27: 2)
    - Antigua (Antigua Union of Teachers, Avonella Thomas), 1978-1979 (Box-folder 27: 3)
    - Bangladesh (Bangladesh Teachers' Association), 1979 (Box-folder 27: 4)
    - Belize (Belize National Teachers' Union, Norman Staines), 1979 (Box-folder 27: 5)
    - Botswana (Kasinathan Perumal), 1979 (Box-folder 27: 6)
    - Congo (Democratic Republic; Mvuemba Kodila), 1979 (Box-folder 27: 7)
    - Costa Rica (Asociacion Nacional de Educadores; Carlos A. Herrera Murillo), 1979 (Box-folder 27: 8)
    - Dominican Republic (Asociacion Dominicana de Profesores), 1977 (Box-folder 27: 9)
    - Ecuador (Union Nacional de Educadores, Julio Ayala S.), 1979-1980 (Box-folder 27: 10)
    - Ghana (Teachers' and Educational Workers' Union), 1979 (Box-folder 27: 11)
    - Honduras (Margaret Hart), 1979 (Box-folder 27: 12)
    - India (All-India Federation of Teachers Organizations), 1979 (Box-folder 27: 13)
    - Israel (Israel Teachers Union, Shalom Levin), 1979 (Box-folder 27: 14)
    - Kenya (Kenya National Union of Teachers), 1979 (Box-folder 27: 15)
    - Korea (Korean Federation of Education Associations, Chong-won Kwak), 1979 (Box-folder 27: 16)
    - Nigeria (Nigeria Union of Teachers, C. O. B. Eche), 1979 (Box-folder 27: 17)
    - Pakistan (Pakistan Lady Teachers' Association), 1979 (Box-folder 27: 18)
    - Philippines (National Alliance of Teachers and Office Workers, Philippine Public School Teachers Association, Santos P. Pascual, Adelisa Almario Raymundo), 1979 (Box-folder 27: 19)
    - Portugal (Sindicato dos Professores da Zona Norte), 1979 (Box-folder 27: 20)
    - St. Vincent (St. Vincent Union of Teachers, Joye Brown), 1979 (Box-folder 27: 21)
    - Sierra Leone (Sierra Leone Teachers Union, Tamba E. Yambasu), 1978-1979 (Box-folder 27: 22)
    - Sri Lanka (Ceylon Tamil Teachers' Union, N. Balasubramaniam), 1979 (Box-folder 27: 23)
    - Taiwan (T. C. Chiang), 1979 (Box-folder 27: 24)
    - Tanzania (K. Kimeza), 1979 (Box-folder 27: 25)
    - Trinidad and Tobago (Trinidad and Tobago Teachers' Union, West Indies Group of University Teachers, St. Elmo Gopaul, Kusha Haraksingh), 1979 (Box-folder 27: 26)
    - Uganda (Uganda Teachers Association), 1979 (Box-folder 27: 27)
    - Zambia (Zambia National Union of Teachers, Shiyenge Kapini), 1978-1979 (Box-folder 27: 28)
  - International Federation of Free Teachers' Unions issuances, 1974-1979
    - 4th Asian Convention, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia, 1976 (Box-folder 27: 29)
      Proceedings.
    - 12th World Congress, Manila, Philippines, 1978 (Box-folder 27: 30)
    - 12th World Congress, Manila, Philippines, 1978 (Box-folder 28: 1)
      Proceedings (cont'd.).
    - Newsletters, 1974-1979 (Box-folder 28: 2)
  - World Confederation of Organizations of the Teaching Profession issuances, 1975-1979
    - Echo, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 28: 3)
    - Press releases, 1975-1978 (Box-folder 28: 4)
  - World Confederation of Teachers issuances, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 28: 5)
    Newsletters and leaflet.
  - World Federation of Teachers' Unions issuances, 1971-1979
    - International Teachers News, 1975-1979 (Box-folder 28: 6)
    - Teachers of the World, 1971-1978 (Box-folder 28: 7)
    - Circular letters, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 28: 8)
  - Subject file, 1972-1979
    Serial issues, newsletters, pamphlets, clippings, and reports.
    - Africa, 1974-1979 (Box-folder 29: 1)
      Includes Yvonne I. Nicholls, A Short History of National Teacher Organizations in Southern Africa and materials by and about the Kenya National Union of Teachers and the Zambia National Union of Teachers.
    - Asia, 1972-1978 (Box-folder 29: 2)
      Includes issuances of the Japan Teachers Union, the Korean Federation of Education Associations, the Sarawak Teachers' Union, and the Taipei Education Association.
    - Belize, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 29: 3)
      Belize National Teachers' Union convention documents.
    - Caribbean region, 1975-1979 (Box-folder 29: 4)
      Includes W. Richard Jacobs, "The Dynamics of Trade Unionism among Intellectual Workers: A Case Study of the West Indies Group of University Teachers, St. Augustine, Trinidad," and issuances of the Antigua Union of Teachers, the Barbados Union of Teachers, the St. Thomas/St. John and St. Croix Federations of Teachers, the St. Vincent Union of Teachers, and the Trinidad and Tobago Teachers' Union.
    - Fiji, 1977 (Box-folder 29: 5)
      Fiji Teachers' Journal (Fiji Teachers' Union).
    - Great Britain, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 29: 6)
      Schoolmaster and Career Teacher (National Association of Schoolmasters/Union of Women Teachers).
    - Israel, 1973 (Box-folder 29: 7)
      Shalom Levin, The Teachers Union in Israel.
    - Philippines, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 29: 8)
      Includes issuances of the Manila Public School Teachers Association, the National Alliance of Teachers and Office Workers, and the Philippine Public School Teachers Association.
    - Singapore, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 29: 9)
      The Mentor (Singapore Teachers' Union).
    - Spain, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 29: 10)
      FETE (Federación de los Trabajadores de la Enseñanza).
- SUBJECT FILE, 1886-1980 (Boxes 30-46)
  Collected serial issues, pamphlets, newsletters, clippings, other printed matter, circulars, leaflets, flyers, programs, and agendas, arranged by topic.
  - Africa, 1964-1978 (Box-folder 30: 1)
  - Americans for Democratic Action, 1952-1966 (Box-folder 30: 2)
    Includes minutes, agenda, and reports of New Jersey and Essex County branches, in which Loewenthal was active.
  - Asia, 1947-1978 (Box-folder 30: 3)
  - Capitalism, 1950-1970 (Box-folder 30: 4)
  - Caribbean region, 1972-1979 (Box-folder 30: 5)
    Includes F. A. Hoyos, Builders of Barbados.
  - Catholic Church, 1939-1965 (Box-folder 30: 6)
    Includes papal encyclicals.
  - Civil rights, 1945-1979
    - General, 1975-1978 (Box-folder 30: 7)
    - New Jersey, 1956-1967 (Box-folder 31: 1)
      Includes lists, programs, financial records, and some correspondence of the Citizens' Committee for Equality in Education, the Fund for Fair Promotional Procedures, the Greater Newark Alliance for Integration and Dignity, the March on Trenton (associated with the March on Washington), the New Jersey Civil Rights Leadership Conference, the New Jersey Conference on Fair Housing, and the Urban League of Essex County, all of which Loewenthal was active in.
    - United States, 1945-1979 (Box-folder 31: 2-3)
      Includes National Community Relations Advisory Council, National Urban League, Push for Excellence, and Washington Full Citizenship Conference issuances.
  - Communism, 1946-1979 (Box-folder 31: 4-5)
  - Economy (international), 1976-1977 (Box-folder 31: 6)
  - Economy--United States, 1957-1979 (Box-folder 32: 1)
  - Education, 1919-1979